# Akiko Iwamizu

SF, CA 94109 | Cell: (818)356-5389 | akikoiwamizu@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/akikoiwamizu | www.akikoiwamizu.com

# **OBJECTIVE**

As an analytical and creative young professional, I am enthusiastic about turning big data into useful insights that drive better business decisions and customer experiences. I am naturally curious and have a sincere passion for both mathematics and programming. With a strong desire to broaden my knowledge, I am able to adapt to new challenges quickly, work independently or within groups on a tight timeline, and effectively communicate to all levels of the organization.

# **EDUCATION**

## BARNARD COLLEGE OF COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY | New York, NY

Sept 2011 - Dec 2014

# Bachelor of Arts in Mathematical Sciences

- Major GPA: 3.4
- Dean's List: Spring 2013, Spring 2014, Fall 2014
- Major Coursework: Calculus I-IV, Linear Algebra, Higher Mathematics, Symbolic Logic, Modern Algebra, Intro to Computer Science: Java Programming, C++ Programming, Statistics and Probability, Data Structures in Java, iOS Programming, Honors Computer Science

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

TIVO INC. | San Jose, CA

Feb 2015 - Present

# Data Scientist

- Programming in R, HiveQL, Python with Pandas, and D3 to identify valuable insights with data
- Translating data into business value in the form of PR releases and product development

TIVO INC. | San Jose, CA

May 2014 - Jan 2015

# Statistical Analyst Intern - Data Science & Internal Analytics Team

- Utilizing SPSS and R to find any correlations within the UX team's survey results
- Using SQL to evaluate viewership and user behavior data
- Working within Amazon Web Services (Hadoop) to observe real-time data logs

#### TIVO RESEARCH AND ANALYTICS | New York, NY

June 2013 – April 2014

### Media Research Analyst and Marketing Intern

- Create models analyzing 10,000 survey completes and TV viewing data from 4 million households to generate insights for content marketing
- Examine TV viewing and grocery purchasing data to inform media buyers and TV networks on how to measure, validate, and optimize their ROI on digital advertisements
- Develop stability scores using R and design algorithms to forecast TV ratings based on the historical patterns pulled from TiVo's database
- Design biweekly email marketing campaigns using MailChimp to reach over 3,000 prospects and clients

# THE TILE APP | San Francisco, CA

June 2013 – Dec 2013

# Software Engineering and Customer Support Intern

- Answer over 5,000 customer inquiries per month
- Apply mathematical analyses to improve the design, development, testing, and evaluation of the Tile App software

### **HUGHES SCIENCE PIPELINE PROJECT** | New York, NY

Aug 2011 - May 2012

#### Research Apprentice

- Identified the sources of water contamination and sent a team to Bangladesh to cleanse the water of 5 communities
- Our research resulted in providing clean water for over 10,000 Bangladeshis

### SKILLS, INTERESTS, & ETC.

- Computer Skills: Excel, Powerpoint, Adobe Suite, WordPress, Email Marketing, Graphic Design, HTML, C++, SPSS, SQL, Java, Git, R, Splunk, HiveQL, Hadoop, AWS, Python, and Database Management
- Languages: English (fluent), Spanish (working proficiency), Japanese (elementary)
- Sports: Running (completed 2 LA marathons), basketball (Spring 2013 co-ed intra championship), and softball
- Hobbies: Botany, crocheting & knitting, and watching Miyazaki/Ghibli Studio movies